SILVIA IOANA CARBUNAREA PRISECARU

silvia.prisecaru@gmail.com +40 727 710 368 https://github.com/silvyshor/

Industries: Nuclear, Biotehnology, Oil&Gas, Automotive, Construction, Geostrategy

Profile:

A financial manager with10y experience in the family business leading several strategic projects across our Factories and Sales companies. A mathematician with inborn leadership skills, using numbers to simplify the decision-making process across companies; using cross-functional teams and persuasion to gain support for my projects.

Professional experience:

2008- present Conex Group (100M EURO, 1200 FTE: ASAM, Conex Distribution, ADIMET, Comes50) Romania 2015 – 2020 Finance Manager

- Managed the turnaround, relocation, strategical repositioning and consolidation process of three factories into ASAM.
 The company gained a healthy liquidity, double-digit increase of activity and reduction of overdraft by 25%.
- Created and managed the relations between family members and managers to oversee: changes in strategy and capital structure, KPIs, investments and sources for financing, overdrafts, securities and covenants, credit insurance.
- Oversaw group processes of Transfer Pricing, Intragroup Balances, External Audit, and ERP architecture.

2011 – 2015 Head of Reporting and Strategy

- Managed the alignment of the management reporting system to lay under an unified guide for reporting standards.
- Implemented Excel templates to map IAS into IFRS, with self-filling predictions for rolling budgets and automated tests for abnormalities detection, dashboards of interconnected Google Sheets with optimum activity level targets.
- Changed the pricing systems and pricing templates through ABC costing in the factories. Ranked products, clients and matched with corresponding markets, based on net profitability/product/hour worked.
- Created a KIT matrix, by working together with engineers in the workcells, holding subassemblies by type and make, before and after machining, both physically and in Excel, to make sure all subassemblies are tightly monitored to increase OTD. Found time in the production line for R&D and optimally scheduled weekly production8.

2012 - 2015 Aktive Media Solution (internet e-commerce platform, website development,) Founder & CEO

Education & awards:

2020-2021 IBM Data Science Professional Certificate (Coursera)

- Python for Data Science and AI, Databases and SQL for Data Science, Data Analysis with Python, Data Visualization with Python, Machine Learning with Python
- Resources: Jupiter Notebooks, Watson Studio. WatsonMachineLearning, DB2-bs, Rstudio, Foursquare

2017 Columbia University in the City of New York : Construction Finance

2015 – present Chartered Institute of Management Accountants, London, United Kingdom

2010 – 2011 Rotterdam School of Management, Erasmus University, Rotterdam, The Netherlands

Msc BA Strategic Management <u>Cum Laude</u> (with distinction)

Dissertation title: "The mediating effect of the alliance portfolio between top management team and performance: a longitudinal study on 538 company-year cases from 55 Biotech entrepreneurial companies present on Nasdaq."

2007 – 2010 Universitatea "Alexandru Ioan Cuza", Iași: <u>GE</u> Global Leadership Scholarship (2009)

1998 – 2007 **Negruzzi Highschool, lasi:** national level Olympiad in Maths and Economy (7th place)

Interests:

Personal interests: Rotaract club member, traveling, reading fiction, running, Sudoku

IT skills: Excel & Google Sheets (advanced), Python & SQL (intermediate), HTML CSS Javascript PHP (basic)

Languages: English (advanced), German(advanced), Spanish (advanced), Russian (intermediate), Dutch (basic)